天呐  冰淇淋  你是想要我命吗
Oh, my god, ice cream? Are you trying to kill me?
至少你会快乐地死去
At least you'll die happy.
你来点
Kate?
不了  谢谢  吃不下了
Oh, no, thanks, I couldn't, not after this
刚刚这顿美餐把我填得饱饱的了
amazing meal that you guys just stuffed us with.
亲爱的  抱歉  甜点可是非吃不可
Oh... darling, I'm sorry. Dessert is not optional,
我为了找到理查德
Not after I traipsed all over town
最喜欢的冰淇淋可是走遍全城
to find Richard his favorite flavor of ice cream.
-薯片软糖  -没错
- Potato chip fudge? - Yes!
贝克特  吃吧
Beckett, dig deep.
万里长征  只差这一步了啊
Come... you would not quit at mile 25 of a marathon.
我们还是中场休息一下
You know what? Why don't we take a break
咱俩刷盘子吧
and you and I do dishes?
想都别想
Oh, don't even think about it.
奶奶和我能搞定的
Gram and I have it covered.
好吧
Okay.
她俩做了饭啊  你不会真让她们洗碗吧
You are not letting them do dishes after they just cooked.
她们喜欢啊
They want to.
你是真要把
You're seriously milking this whole
"我失踪两个月"当做资本  讨好处  是吧
"I've been missing for two months thing," aren't you?
她们很高兴我能回来
They are glad to have me back,
如果对我关照得无微不至能让她们开心
and if fussing over me makes them happy...
那就偷乐嘛
Enjoy it.
你也该尝尝这个
Like you ought to be enjoying this
薯片软糖冰淇淋圣代
potato chip fudge ice cream sundae.
有种又咸又甜的味道
It's got that whole salty/sweet thing going on.
跟我一样
It's just... just like me.
我来接吧
I'll... I'll get yeah. I'll get it. Mm.
贝克特的电话
Beckett's phone.
我知道你才回来几周
Look, I know that you've only been back
我们都还在适应这一点
for a few weeks, and we're all still trying to process it,
但我得说
but I gotta say,
阿丽克西斯对你那么关照
Alexis waiting on you hand and foot...
实在好怪
it's just it's a little odd.
你知道什么才叫怪吗
Hey, you know what's really odd?
冰淇淋车开到这么荒无人烟的地方
Ice cream truck in the middle of nowhere.
这里才没有小孩会来排队买糖呢
There's no kids lining up to buy bomb pops around here.
是啊  这里一定不是常规行车路线
Yeah, this couldn't have been the driver's route.
差远了  我刚刚跟冰淇淋车的
Not even close. I just got off the phone
车主通过电话
with the owner of the ice cream truck...
谢尔盖·维托什金
Sergei Vetotchkin.
死者是他儿子  安东  22岁
The victim is his son... Anton, 22.
早上5点发现他死在车座上
They found him behind the wheel around 5:00 p.m.
这世上没有神圣的东西了吗
Is nothing sacred?
谁会杀冰淇淋车售货员啊
I mean, who kills an ice cream man,
这可是童真的象征
a symbol of childhood innocence?
或许有人是想抢他钱
Maybe someone wanted his money.
但是今天的收入都还在车上
Except that today's cash receipts were still in the van.
而且凶手是近距离开枪
And whoever did this shot him at close range.
胸口两处枪伤  有焦痕
Two G.S.W.s to the chest with powder burns.
我们认为凶手登上车
We figure the shooter boarded the truck
射死了安东  然后把他抬回座位里
and shot Anton, knocking him back into the shifter.
挂一档  车慢慢开到了这里
Went into first, and that's why the truck rolled here.
凶手大概从车后逃离的
Killer probably bolted out the back.
有人看到了吗
Anyone see it?
我们派了警员在这里找目击者
We got unis canvassing for witnesses,
但这一带没什么人
but it's not exactly an area where people hang out.
那街头监控呢
And what about street cams?
覆盖不全  如果有发现真是撞大运了
Coverage is spotty. We'll get really lucky if we get a hit.
这孩子为什么来这一带啊
What was this kid doing here in the first place?
我不知道我们儿子为什么去那一带
I don't know why our son would be in that neighborhood.
我们不是在那里做生意的
That's not where we do business.
他有没有可能卷进什么
Well, is it possible that he was involved
危险的事中
in something that would take him down there,
才会去那边
something dangerous?
不  安东是个好孩子
No. Anton was...A good boy.
他从没惹过麻烦
Never got in trouble.
他行车线路上有什么麻烦吗
Were there any troubles on his route?
他生活中有什么异常吗
Anything unusual going on in his life?
他早下学回家了
He came home early from school.
他去哪所学校
What school did he go to?
他在布朗克斯的社区大学夜校
He was taking night classes at the community college
学平面设计
in the Bronx for graphic design.
他小时候在阿布哈兹就喜欢画画
Since he was a boy in Abkhazia, he loved to draw.
但昨晚  他从学校回来时
But last night, he came back from class
十分不安  似乎是出事了
very upset, like something was wrong.
是啊  当时的确不对劲
Yeah, there was definitely something wrong.
我从没见过安东那副样子
I'd never seen Anton like that before.
能跟我们说说情况吗
Could you tell us what happened?
我给了他一项课业任务
Yeah, I'd given the class an assignment,
安东像其他人一样在自己的工作台做设计
and Anton was working at his station like everyone else,
突然之间  他就开始颤抖  似乎很害怕
and all of a sudden he started shaking like he was terrified.
因为什么
Because of what?
不知道  他随后跑出了教室
I don't know. He ran out of the room.
但后来我在停车场
But I saw him later in the parking lot
看见他上了一个男人的车
getting into a car with some guy.
什么男人  能描述一下吗
What guy? Can you describe him?
太暗了
No, it was too dark, but...
我记得那辆车
I-I do remember the car.
亮绿色  老款凯美瑞
It was bright green, an old Camry.
你记得车牌吗
Did you happen to get a license plate?
我记得有3  E和K
I-I got a 3, an "E," and a "K."
你说他是在工作台上突然发作
You said this all started when he was at his station.
能让我们看下他之前在忙些什么吗
Can we take a look at what he was working on?
可以  我得先登录系统
Uh, yeah. I have to log you into the system.
怎么会这样
What the - -
他的文件夹不见了  而且他的
His portfolio is gone and all his...
作业也被删除了
projects have been deleted.
是安东自己删除的吗  他为什么这么做
Did Anton delete them? Why would he do that?
我不知道
I have no idea.
是鉴证组  我是莱恩
It's C.S.U. Ryan.
莱恩
Ryan?
鉴证组有发现
Hey. C.S.U. got us a lead.
看这个柜子的关合状态
See how this cabinet door is open?
跟凶案现场的照片一样
Just like in these crime scene photos.
嗯  是一样的  那又如何
Okay. So?
当柜子右边的门关上的时候
So when the cabinet door is closed...
左边原先被遮盖的地方也有血迹
There's blood spatter on the door panel behind it.
说明安东被杀的时候右边的门是关上的
Which means the door was closed when Anton was shot.
对  现在你们再看门内面
Yep. Now, see this smear of blood
边缘处的血印
on the inside edge of the door?
鉴证组的人说这是手指印造成的
C.S.U. said that this came from a finger,
所以有人从柜子里面
So somebody grabbed the door from the inside,
打开了门
pulling it open.
如果安东被杀时有人在里面
If someone was in there when Anton was shot...
-他就看见了杀人凶手  -有目击证人
- They saw our killer. - A witness.
不是这么简单  我猜测目击证人也许是个孩子
Yeah, not only that, I think our witness might be a kid.
你说什么
What?
这是他落在柜子里的
They left that on the inside of the cabinet.
是一张班级郊游的许可征询信
It's a permission slip for a class trip.
无法从上面套取有用的指纹
No usable prints on it,
但的确是今天的日期
But it does have today's date.
肯尼迪小学
Kennedy elementary.
离这不到一英里
That's less than a mile away.
假设下午放学后
Assuming an afternoon dismissal,
安东被杀时大概是下午5点
Anton was shot at 5:00 p.m.
安东被杀时一位肯尼迪小学的学生在货车里
Someone from that school was in this van when Anton was killed.
是鲁伊兹老师二年级班上的学生
Someone from Miss Ruiz's second grade class.
我不敢相信是鲁伊兹老师班上的学生
I can't imagine it's one of Mrs. Ruiz's students.
他们怎么会自己跑到那去
Why would they even be in that area alone?
等我们警官跟他们聊完后
Well, we'll know more once our youth officer
就知道了
is done talking to them.
昨天鲁伊兹老师班上
Now, what time did...
是几点下课的
Mrs. Ruiz's class let out yesterday?
3点放学的   而且每个孩子都是由
At 3 p.m., and each child was picked up
父母或者合法的监护人接走的
by a parent or authorized guardian.
我需要一份他们的名单
Okay, and I'm gonna need a list of all of their names
这样我们才能推断出下午5点他们大概在什么地方
so we can determine where they were at 5:00 p.m.
-没问题  -贝克特警探
- Of course. - Detective Deckett?
我和鲁伊兹老师和所有的学生都谈过了
Mrs. Ruiz and I talked to all the students.
没人看起来像是目击者
None of them seems to be your witness.
但是肯定有一个是
Except one of them has to be.
也许我们应该再跟他们聊一次
You know, maybe we should talk to them again.
如果他们害怕说出来  再来一次也没多大帮助
If they're afraid to come forward, that's not gonna help.
又或者他们什么都没看见
Or perhaps they didn't see anything.
不管怎样  他们也不该被无休止的问题
Either way, these children shouldn't be subjected
-一直纠缠下去  -我明白
- to endless questions. - I know, I understand,
但我们必须找到目击证人
But we have to find this witness.
像这种情况  孩子更容易像
In cases like this, a child is often more likely
非官方的人袒露心扉
to open up to somebody who's not an authority figure - -
同学或者朋友
A classmate, a friend.
所以我们要找一个
So, basically, we're looking for someone
不会让他们觉得有压迫感的人
who won't intimidate them.
一个出现在教室里
An adult presence in the classroom
会被八岁的孩子当做是
that 8- year- olds will view as a peer,
他们同伴的成年人
someone that they can consider one of their own?
好吧  可我们去哪找这样的人呢
Okay, but where would we find someone like that?
通关了
Got it.
太简单了
Easy.
谢谢你  鲁伊兹老师
Thank you, Mrs. Ruiz,
同意让卡塞尔占用你的课堂时间
For letting Castle spend time in your classroom.
我没什么选择
I wasn't given much of a choice.
对此我们深表歉意
Well, then we apologize for the imposition,
但我们的确需要找到目击证人
but we do need to figure out who this witness is.
你们打算怎么做
And just how are you going to do that?
你知道我们已经跟他们都谈过了  对吗
You know we spoke to all of them already, right?
我不一样  我有儿童一般的心
Yes, but being 90% kid myself,
我知道他们在想什么
I have an ability to get into the minds of children.
而且我有个完美的计划
And I have the perfect plan.
相信我  不可能的
Trust me, there is no such thing.
卡塞尔先生  你有曾和
Have you ever been in a room
20个二年级学生待在一起的经历吗
with 20 second- graders, Mr. Castle?
谢谢你的关心  莱斯丽
I appreciate your concern, Leslie.
我能叫你莱斯丽吗
May I call you Leslie?
-鲁伊兹老师比较合适  -了解
- "Mrs. Ruiz" Is fine.  Excellent.
我有信心  对这些小鬼
I'm sure I'm more than capable of handling
我能应付自如
anything these little charmers can throw my way.
别担心  只是个橡皮擦
In this case, is an eraser.
你们有什么发现吗
Hey, what do you got?
我们根据安东老师提供的
We chased down that partial plate
零星的车牌资料查了下
that Anton's teacher gave us.
她看见的那辆车吗
That car she saw?
发现车子注册在一位已退休的
Looks like it's registered to a retired cop
名叫克拉克·杰菲的警察名下
named Clark Jaffe.
-警察  -对
- A cop? - Yeah.
安东那晚给他打了个电话
Anton placed a call to him that night from
用的是校外的付费电话
the pay phone outside the college.
好  带他回来
Okay, bring him in.
怕是不行了
That's gonna be a problem.
他已经死了  被枪杀的
Jaffe's dead. Shot to death.
他也被枪杀了  什么时候
He was shot, too? When?
昨天  安东遇害前八小时左右
Yesterday, about eight hours before Anton.
我进行了弹道对比  吻合
And I ran ballistics. It's a match.
是同一个凶手
It's the same shooter.
好  我马上来
Okay. I'm on my way.
大家伙儿  注...
Hey, everybody. Atten--
注意  喂  大家都注意
Attention, everyone! Hello! Attention!
伙计们
Guys.
同学们
Class.
绝招啊
Neat trick.
孩子们  这位是卡塞尔先生
Children, this is Mr. Castle.
今天的课将由他来帮我上
He's gonna be helping me with today's lessons.
早上好  卡塞尔先生
Good morning, Mr. Castle.
好了  大侦探  该你上了
Okay, Columbo. You're on.
好
Right.
同学们  早上好
Good morning, class.
咱们有谁知道什么是作家吗
Does anyone here know what a writer is?
-你说  -作家就是写故事的
- Yes? - A writer writes stories.
非常正确
That's exactly right.
那么...有谁认识任何作家吗
And...who here knows a writer?
真无聊
This is boring!
鲁伊兹老师说我可以展示我的拍立得
Mrs. Ruiz said I can show-and-tell my instant camera!
稍等会吧  杰森
Maybe later, Jason.
你说
Yes?
卡塞尔先生  你不是就作家吗
Mr. Castle, aren't you a writer?
事实上  我还真是
Well, as a matter of fact, I am.
你有名吗
Are you famous?
我不确定"有名"这个词是否恰当
Well, I don't know if I'd use the word "Famous."
-有人...  -我爸爸说你的书很烂
-Some people... - my dad says your books suck.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle!
我的课堂上不能做鬼脸
We do not make faces in my classroom.
是他先的
He started it!
你说你有计划来着
You said you had a plan?
对  我有计划
Yes, yes, I have a plan.
除了我  还有人认识其他作家吗
Aside from me, does anyone here know another writer?
这样吧  所有人向左看
Tell you what. Everyone look to your left.
你们看到的都是作家
You're looking at a writer.
除了最后一列的同学  你们看的是墙
Except for you guys on the end. You're looking at the wall.
我们都是作家
We are all writers.
如果你会讲故事  你就能写故事
If you can tell a story, you can write a story.
所以...
So...
咱们现在就开始吧  咱们来写个故事
Let's do that right now. Let's write a story.
主角可以是一个小男孩
It can be about a little boy
或是小女孩  就像你们一样
or a little girl, just like you.
情节可以搞笑也可以恐怖  随你们发挥
It can be as silly or as scary as you want it to be.
我能写一个过家家的故事吗
Can I write about having a tea party?
当然可以
Of course you can.
卡塞尔先生  我可以编故事吗
Mr. Castle, is it okay to make things up?
当然可以  你们可以编故事
Of course, yes. You can make things up,
又或者  你们可以
Or you could, um, you could write it
改写生活中真实发生过的事
based on something that happened in real life.
大家都准备好了吗
Is everyone ready?
开始
Uh, go!
找到两名受害者之间的联系了吗
We found a link between our two vics?
除了知道安东那晚上了杰菲的车
Other than Anton getting in Jaffe's car that night,
其他还没有  而且安东没有案底
not so far, and Anton's never been in trouble with the law.
问过安东的父母了吗
You talk to Anton's parents?
问了  他们从没听说过杰菲
Yeah, they never heard of Jaffe.
我跟你说  这两个人
I'm telling you, these guys,
他们住在不同的街区
they lived in different neighborhoods,
结交的是不同的圈子
they moved in different circles.
他们一起开车离开的
They drive off together,
然后第二天两人都死了
and then the next day they both end up dead?
他们一定有关联  我们要查出来
They're connected. We just gotta find out how.
还有点发现  克拉克·杰菲遇害后
I got something else. After Clark Jaffe was killed,
有人翻过他的家
someone tossed his place.
凶手在找什么东西
Killer was looking for something.
不多喝点水的话  他们能把你累死
If you don't hydrate, they'll eat you alive.
谢谢  你真好
Ah, thank you. That's very kind.
他们写的故事怎么样了
So, how are those stories they wrote?
别客气  我的桌子尽管用
Oh, and feel free to use my desk.
我...只是
I was.. I just...
你不太喜欢我  对吧
You don't like me very much, do you?
不是  卡塞尔先生
That's not it, Mr. Castle.
他们还是孩子
These are kids,
我有责任保护他们
and it's my job to protect them,
即便对方是出于好意
even from people who mean well.
而且  如果他们真有人看到了什么
Besides, if one of them did see something,
他都吓得没勇气说出来
They're too afraid to come forward.
你又怎么能指望他会写下来呢
So why would you expect them to write about?
我没有  起码不是直接写下来
Well, I don't. Well, not directly.
但一段那么让人难忘的经历
But an experience that powerful
总会想办法自己浮出水面
is going to find a way to express itself
最后就会落于纸上
and end up on the page.
再天马行空的想象也是基于事实基础的
Even the wildest fantasy is based on a kernel of truth.
作为一个故事大师
As a master storyteller, I'm able to separate
我能从细微的痕迹中分辨出事实和虚构
the make-believe from the telltale details of thinly veiled fact.
记住我的话  鲁伊兹老师
You mark my words, Mrs. Ruiz...
这堆东西中的某处
Somewhere in this pile is the key
有我们找到目击者的关键
to identifying our witness.
我查了杰菲的车
I followed up on Jaffe's car.
没有导航  没有收费系统的记录
There's no G.P.S., no E-ZPass.
完全没有办法
There's no way of finding out
知道他和安东那晚去了哪里
where he and Anton went that night.
好吧  你的财务状况调查如何
Okay, what about you on financials?
作为前警察  他的生活比和尚还简谱
For an ex-cop, the guy lived like a monk.
安东也是  而这正是我们的麻烦所在
So did Anton, which is part of our problem.
那孩子没手机  没信用卡记录
The kid had no cell phone, no credit cards to pull.
他们俩一定有联系
There's got to be a connection between these two guys.
但我就是找不到
I'm just not finding it.
但我不理解的是
But here's what I don't get --
22岁的一个卖冰淇淋的
what's a 22-year-old ice cream man
能和一个前任警察有什么关系呢
doing with an ex-cop, anyway?
关于这事我可能有线索了
I may have a lead on that.
我调查了那辆冰淇淋车
I was looking into the ice cream truck.
上周在马布尔山被贴了罚单
It was ticketed last week up on Marble Hill,
-但那根本不在安东的路线上  -于是
- which is nowhere near Anton's route. - So?
于是我调查了克拉克·杰菲的财务状况
So I checked into Clark Jaffe's financials.
杰菲的信用卡显示他恰在当天
Jaffe's credit card shows that he parked at a meter
用过同一条街的停车场
the exact same block on the same day.
这绝不是巧合
That's not a coincidence.
这是当天拍到安东的车的交通监控录像
This is traffic cam footage of Anton's truck that day.
看
Now watch.
他进了那家物流店
He goes into that shipping store.
他去那干什么
What's he doing in there?
不知道  但我仔细看了一遍录像
I have no idea. But I scrubbed all the footage.
这是一小时前的
This is from an hour earlier.
绿色凯美瑞
A green camry.
和克拉克·杰菲
And that's Clark Jaffe.
进了同一家店
Going into the same store.
他们俩去那儿干什么
So what were the two of them doing?
我找到啦
I found it!
我想我找到目击者了
I think I found our witness!
就是这份  是杰克
Right here. It's Jack.
他写了一个关于邪恶巨人的故事
He wrote a story about an evil giant,
从孩子的角度看
which, from a child's perspective,
就是凶手应有的形象
is how the killer would seem.
他说那个巨人声音很大很生气
He said that the giant spoke in a loud, angry voice,
说话很凶  而且说他要伤害别人
said mean things, and promised he would hurt someone.
那不过是杰克与豌豆的故事
That's just "Jack and the Beanstalk."
没错  但他的故事里  巨人有把枪
Yes, but in this story, the giant had a gun.
好吧  就算你是对的
Okay. Let's say you're right.
假设杰克当时真藏在冰淇淋车里
Let's say Jack was hiding in the ice cream truck,
而且他太害怕不愿说出来
and he's afraid to tell anyone.
你又怎么让他告诉你呢
How are you gonna get him to tell you?
继续前进  前进
Keep moving! Move up!
停止前进  兄弟们  掩护我
Hold back, guys! Cover me!
干掉他们啦
Got 'em!
干的好  等等
Nice work! Whoa! Wait a minute.
我想我看到前方出现了更多坏人
I think I see more bad guys ahead.
怎么了
What?
有个巨人
There's a giant.
他有没有
And does he...
没错  他拿着一把枪
Yeah. He does. He's got a gun.
糟糕  快趴下  他要开枪了
No! Get down! He's gonna shoot it!
你这么觉得吗
You think?
上次就是这样  他说  我要开枪了
He did last time. He said, "I'm gonna shoot."
然后他就开枪了
Then he did.
-上次  就像你的故事吗  -是
- Last time, like in your story? - Yes.
他开枪了  砰砰
He shot his gun -- bing, bing!
然后另一个人就流血了
And then the other guy was bleeding.
不过
Only...
这并不是个故事  对吗  杰克
it wasn't a story, was it, Jack?
这是真的
It really happened.
我好害怕  我闭上了眼睛
I was scared. I closed my eyes
直到巨人消失
until the giant disappeared.
哥们儿  你很勇敢
Hey, man, you are very brave.
我哥哥不是这么说的
That's not what my brother said.
你哥哥也在
Your brother was there?
他说  别当胆小鬼了  这只是电影
He said, "Don't be a chicken. It's just a stupid movie."
然后他就换台了
Then he changed the channel.
-巨人是在电视上的  -是的
- The giant was on TV? - Yeah.
卡塞尔先生尿裤子了  卡塞尔先生尿裤子了
Mr. Castle wet his pants! Mr. Castle wet his pants!
没有  这是因为草坪是湿的
No, no -- see, the ground was wet!
安东和杰菲先生  他们常来
Yeah. Anton and Mr. Jaffe. They come in here a lot.
安东六个月前租了个
Anton rented a P.O. box here
邮政信箱  552号
about six months ago, box 552.
他和杰菲一起用
And he shared it with Jaffe.
-他们共用一个邮政信箱  -是的
- They were sharing a P.O. box? - Yeah.
他们收到的都是什么样的邮件
What kind of mail were they getting?
奇怪的就在这儿  他们没收到过邮件
That's the thing. They weren't getting any mail.
至少我没见过
At least not that I ever saw.
那他们用这邮箱干什么
Then why did they need the box?
我只知道他们都每两周来查看一次
All I know is they both came in twice a week to check it.
-一起吗  -不是
- Together? - No.
一般隔一小时左右
Usually about an hour apart.
这是他们的情报秘密传递点
They were using it as a dead drop.
没错  但传递的是什么呢
Yeah, but for what?
你最后一次见他们是什么时候
Uh -- when was the last time you saw them?
上周他们两个我都见过
I saw 'em both last week.
但昨天安东又来了
But Anton came in yesterday.
而且我告诉他那通电话的事后
And he seemed a little worked up
他看起来有点激动
after I told him about the phone call I'd got.
哪通电话
What phone call?
一个俄国口音的人打来的
Some dude with a Russian accent
问我说552号邮箱是谁的
called asking me who owned box 552 --
就是安东的那个
Anton's box.
我跟他说我们不能提供客户信息
I told the caller we don't give out that kind of information,
但当我跟安东说起此事时
but when I mentioned the call to Anton,
他突然失控了
He flipped out.
这么说安东认识这个人
So Anton knew this guy.
-是  -我也这么认为  因为他非常慌张
- Yeah. - I guess so, 'cause he went into total panic mode,
说要打个电话
Said he had to use the phone.
但我不能让他打
But I couldn't let him use it.
因为这违法了公司的规定
It's against company policy,
于是他就跑了出去
So he just raced out of here.
那是什么时间
What time was that?
-三点  -好的  谢了
- 3:00. - Okay, thanks.
下午三点  两个小时后安东就被杀了
3:00 P.M.? That's two hours before Anton was killed.
看来这个俄国人是来干掉他的
Sounds like this Russian dude was coming for him.
你觉得安东是想打给谁  杰菲吗
Who do you think Anton was trying to call -- Jaffe?
或者是另一个与这些事有关系的人
Or someone else connected to all of this.
安东没有手机
Look, Anton didn't have a cell,
所以如果他真想打电话  那一定就在附近
so if he really needed to make a call, he'd go nearby.
我会排查这里所有的商店
I'll canvass all the stores in the area,
看看有没有人让安东打过电话
see if anyone let Anton use their phone.
很好  学校快要放学了
Great. And, school's almost out.
我去接卡塞尔  看看他有没有
I'll get ahold of Castle and see if he's gotten
找到目击者
any closer to finding our witness.
还没有进展
No, no breakthroughs yet,
不过  好消息是
But, the good news is -- is,
他们好像已经把我当作他们的一员了
it looks like they've accepted me as one of their own.
各位  把钱包还给我  那是别人送的礼物
Okay, guys, give me the wallet. That was a gift.
等等  你那边到底什么情况
Wait, what is going on over there?
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
没有  一切顺利  晚上再谈
No, everything's fine. I'll talk to you tonight.
好的  再见
Okay, bye-bye.
好了  小家伙们  很好玩
Okay, guys, very funny.
快把钱包还给我
Give me back the wallet now.
鲁伊兹老师  能帮个忙吗
Mrs. Ruiz, a little help here?
-这里  这里  -不帮吗
- Here! Here! Here! - No?
好吧  这有点...
Okay, that's get-- okay.
孩子们  去走廊站好队准备放学
Children, line up in the hall for dismissal.
卡塞尔先生  你还好吗
Mr. Castle, are you okay?
是的  我没事
Yes, I am.
我很好  谢谢你  艾米丽  你真好
I'm fine. Thank you, Emily. Very kind.
我知道这种感觉
I know how it feels.
有时我也会遇到不好的事
Sometimes bad things happen to me, too.
是吗
They do?
很不好的事
Really bad things --
今天早晨鲁伊兹老师问我的时候
Things I didn't want to tell Mrs. Ruiz
我不想告诉她
when she asked me this morning.
什么事呢
Well, things like what?
比如昨天  我...
Like yesterday, I was...
艾米丽  快过来 亲爱的
Emily? Come along, dear.
我们去看医生不能迟到
We don't want to be late for the doctor.
你明天会来吗
Will you be here tomorrow?
一定来
You can count on it.
埃斯波西托跟艾米丽的父母的确认了
So Esposito confirmed with Emily's parents
那天她14岁的哥哥应该负责
that her 14-year-old brother was supposed to be
看着她的  可是他当时在玩游戏
watching her that day, but he was playing video games
好几个小时都没有看她
and he didn't check on her for hours.
这么说她可能溜出去了
So she could have sneaked out.
就是她  贝克特  我确定
It is her, Beckett. I knew it!
所以我们昨晚就应该去她家跟她谈
Which is why we should have talked to her at her place last night.
不顾把她吓到吗  不行  不行
And risk intimidating her? No, no.
这个小女孩  她已经准备好要跟我说了
This girl's -- she's ready to open up to me.
我们有种  特别的感情
We have a... a special connection.
是吗  我需要担心吗
Really? Should I be worried?
只需要担心我会比你先破案
Only that I'm gonna solve the case before you.
你们要去哪
Where do you think you're going?
二年级教室
Second grade.
要吃完早餐才能走
Not without finishing your breakfast.
我基本吃完了  而且我要迟到了
I ate most of it, and I'm just -- I'm late.
拜托  老爸  就再吃一口
Come on, dad, just one more bite.
阿丽克西斯  我不...
Alexis, I'm not --
别忘了你的午餐
Now don't forget your lunch.
好吧  你说得对
Okay. You're right.
她的确有点怪异  我会跟她谈的
It's weird. I'll talk to her.
-好  -不过现在...
- Okay. - But right now...
我要赶紧去过家家了
I'm late for a tea party.
非常感谢
Thank you so mu--
倒得好多
Oh, that's plenty.
这茶是你自己泡的吗
Did you make this tea yourself?
不得不说  太好喝了
I have to say, it's excellent.
-谢谢  -不  应该谢谢你
- Thank you. - No, thank you.
你要加糖吗
Do you want some sugar?
其实我正在减肥
Actually, I'm trying to cut back.
你有低能量仙尘吗
Do you have any low-calorie fairy dust?
谢谢
Thank you.
太好了
Perfect.
太好喝了  非常感谢
Delicious. Thank you very much.
也谢谢你课间跟我一起玩
And thank you for spending recess with me.
不客气
You're welcome.
你想建一座冰宫吗
Do you want to build an ice palace?
这是我最喜欢的事
It's only my favorite thing to do.
开始吧
Here we go.
太漂亮了
Oh, they are nice.
艾米丽  你还记得吗  昨天你跟我说
You know, Emily, do you remember yesterday
你遇到了非常不好的事情
you said that something really bad happened,
那事情...
something...
你造的墙太高了
You're making the wall too high.
抱歉
Oh. Sorry.
这样好一些了吗
Is that better?
好了
All right.
你说有些事情
You said it was something
你不想告诉鲁伊兹老师
that you didn't want to tell Mrs. Ruiz about.
那你想跟我说说吗
Do you think maybe you'd want to tell me?
好吧
Okay.
你知道  如果你愿意可以跟我说说
You know, you could -- if you wanted.
就好像一位公主对另一位公主
It would just be... one princess to another.
因为公主们要互相帮助吗
Because princesses help each other?
因为公主们要互相帮助
Because princesses help each other.
这和杰森有关
It's about Jason.
杰森  那个做鬼脸的小孩吗
Jason -- that kid who makes faces, Jason?
他欺负人
He's a bully.
他说一些难听的话还扯我的头发
He says mean things and pulls my hair.
今天早上他踩了我的脚  故意的
This morning, he stepped on my foot -- on purpose.
艾米丽  你知道为什么人会做不好的事吗
Emily, do you know why people do mean things?
因为这样会让他们觉得自己很坚强
'Cause it makes 'em feel strong.
真的  可你和我  我们本身就很坚强
Really, though, you and me, we're the strong ones.
我们只是把我们的力量放在心里
We just keep our strength inside.
以至于有时候我们自己都会忘了它的存在
So sometimes we forget it's there.
就好像有时候我忘了我口袋里有口香糖
Like sometimes I forget I have gum in my pocket.
是的  所以下次杰森再欺负你
Exactly. So, next time Jason does something mean,
你要拿出勇气  释放它
you just use that strength and just let it go.
当他发现无法使你生气  他就不会来烦你
When he sees he can't upset you, he'll stop bothering you.
好吗
Okay?
我能出去玩了吗
Can I go out and play now?
当然  这些盘子我来洗
Of course. I'll take care of these dishes
宫殿我会来完成的
and finish the palace.
不是她  对吗
Not her, huh?
来吧  你就幸灾乐祸吧
Go ahead. Gloat.
可能这就是个愚蠢的想法
Maybe this was a dumb idea.
当然是
Oh, it was.
但这个笨办法
But...that dumb idea
也让艾米丽对你吐露了心声
got Emily to confide in you.
他们渐渐信任你了  卡塞尔先生
You're earning their trust, Mr. Castle.
我想是的  不是吗
I guess I am, aren't I?
如果你让艾米丽对你敞开心扉
And if you got Emily to open up to you,
接下来的事谁知道呢
then who knows?
可能那个目击者也会这样的
Maybe that witness really will come forward.
谢谢你
Thank you...
莱斯丽
Leslie?
还是叫我鲁伊兹老师好点
Still Mrs. Ruiz. Right.
天呐
Oh, dear!
让一下
Please!
她一拳打在我鼻子上
She punched me in the nose!
这是我内心的力量
It was my inside strength.
我释放它了  就像卡塞尔先生说的那样
I let it go, like Mr. Castle said.
-你让她揍我  -什么  不是的杰森
- You told her to hit me?! - What?! No, Jason --
我要告诉校长
I'm gonna tell the principal!
我  那是
I'm -- that was --
卡塞尔先生  我确定这件事情
Mr. Castle, I'm sure that this is being
被搞得过分严重了  但我实话实说
blown out of proportion, but I'll be candid.
杰森的父母是非常厉害的律师
Jason's parents are two high-powered lawyers
对起诉有着非一般的热情
with a zest for litigation.
我们刚刚决定最好还是不要惹怒他们
We found out a while ago that it's best not to upset them.
你的意思是
So what are you saying?
我们已经试过了
We gave this experiment a fair shot,
但是现在我们得向前看了
but now we have to move on.
席尔瓦校长拜托  我只需要多一点时间
Principal Silva, please -- I just need a little more time.
我也希望能相信你  卡塞尔先生
I wish that I could believe that, Mr. Castle,
但你在寻找目击证人这件事上
but have you made any progress in identifying
有什么进展吗
this supposed witness?
任何的进展
Any progress at all?
从财务情况上看不出任何线索
Nothing pops with this financials.
如果安东和杰菲是利用那个邮箱
If Anton and Jaffe were doing anything illegal
进行非法活动  他们也赚不到什么钱
with that P.O. box, they weren't making much money.
克拉克·杰菲任职了30年
Clark Jaffe put in 30 years.
他受过表彰直到退休也没有任何污点记录
He retired with commendations and a spotless service record.
为什么像他那样的人会犯法呢
Why would someone like him break the law?
对安东我也有同样的疑问
I'm asking the same thing about Anton.
我们最需要的就是卡塞尔寻找的目击证人
What we really need is Castle's witness.
排查有线索了
Yo. Canvass got a hit.
邮箱存放店旁边的一个酒窖老板说
The owner of a bodega near that mailbox store
安东非常惊慌地进来使用了电话
said that Anton came in all desperate to use the phone.
-这个人让他打了电话  -给谁
- The guy let him make a call. - To whom?
这个人  德米特里·拉伦科夫
To this guy. Dmitri Kalenkov.
他2003年移民到美国
He emigrated to the U.S. in '03
有传闻说他是俄国黑手党的打手
and is rumored to be an enforcer for the Bratva.
俄罗斯集团犯罪
Russian organized crime?
等等
Wait a minute.
那个来询问邮箱的人
The guy who called asking about the P.O. Box --
不也是俄国人吗  如果那人就是德米特里
Wasn't he Russian, too? What if that was Dmitri,
会不会他就是杀害杰菲和安东的凶手
and he's the one that took out Jaffe and Anton?
可能他们做了一些非法的勾当
Maybe they were involved in something illegal,
不管那是什么  跟俄国犯罪团伙有关
and whatever it was stepped on Russian mob turf.
所以安东给德米特里打电话来调解
So Anton called Dmitri to smooth things over.
结果最后胸口挨了两枪
And ended up taking two in the chest.
谢谢
Thanks, l.T.
集团犯罪组刚拿到德米特里现在的住址
Organized crime just got a current address on dmitri.
-纽约警局  -德米特里·拉伦科夫
- N.Y.P.D.! - Dmitri Kalenkov!
-纽约警局  -举起手来  举起手来
- N.Y.P.D.! - Hands up! Hands up!
-纽约警局  -举起手来  德米
- N.Y.P.D.! - Hands up, Dmi--
这味道真是
That smells good.
找到他了
Found him!
这就是德米特里
It's Dmitri.
他被人枪杀了
He's been shot.
已经死了好几天了
Been dead at least a couple of days.
贝克特  过来看看
Hey, Beckett, check it out.
电缆  汽车电池  导线
Electrical cable, car battery, leads.
他先被折磨过
He was tortured first.
某人曾在这里被折磨过
Well, someone might have been tortured here,
不过不是德米特里
but it wasn't Dmitri.
你确定
Are you sure?
我发现的伤口除了枪伤
The only injury I see besides bullet wounds
就是他脑后的钝器外伤
is a blunt-force trauma to the back of the head,
根据创面的情况来看
And by the look of the contusion,
我认为凶器是那把断掉的座椅扶手
I would say it was made by that broken chair arm.
假如被折磨的不是德米特里
So if Dmitri wasn't tortured,
可能他就是负责折磨的人
maybe he was the one doing the torturing.
正符合他黑帮打手的身份
It fits the profile of a mob enforcer.
就是说那个被绑在椅子上的人挣脱了
Which means whoever was tied into that chair broke free,
制住了德米特里  然后枪杀了他
overpowered Dmitri, and then shot him.
他死了有多久了
How long has he been dead?
至少有三天时间
I'd say at least three days.
那德米特里是在杰菲和安东之前被杀的
So Dmitri was killed before Jaffe and Anton.
而且很有可能是同一杀手所为
And most likely by the same shooter.
同样胸口上开了两枪
Same two taps to the chest.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
为什么要杀害一个黑帮打手
Why kill a mob enforcer,
一个卖冰激凌的和一个退休警察
an ice cream man, and a retired cop?
他们到底卷入什么事情了
What were they mixed up in?
我不知道
I don't know,
但这看上去和俄国有很大关系
but it's starting to look like a Russian thing.
安东  德米特里还有那个给邮箱店打电话的人
Anton, Dmitri, the guy who called the mailbox store.
再和有组织犯罪调查科联系看看
Okay, touch base with Organized Crime again.
让他们查查俄罗斯社区里有什么冲突
Let's see if there's a conflict in the Russian community.
好的
All right.
是安东的父母那边
Hey. That was Anton's parents.
有人闯进了他们的公寓还翻了个底朝天
Someone just broke into their apartment and tossed the place.
这和杰菲的住所被翻过一样
Just like Jaffe's place was tossed.
凶手正在找某个东西
The killer's after something.
某个这些被害者拥有的东西
Something that our victims had.
是的  但是什么呢
Yeah, but what?
再见  亲爱的
Goodbye. Bye, sweetheart.
再见  菲奥娜  再见  琼
Bye, Fiona. Bye, June.
-再见  苏菲  -谢谢你  卡塞尔先生
- Bye, Sophie. - Thank you, Mr. Castle.
-再见  莎拉  -再见了
- Bye, Sarah, bye. - Bye.
要开开心心的  小朋友
Have a good one, buddy.
杰克  在战场上的时候一定要保持警惕
Jack, you make sure you keep your guard up on that battlefield,
记住了吗
all right?
-再见  亲爱的  -再见了
- All right. Bye, sweetheart. - Bye.
你真的要走了吗
You're leaving?
是的  艾米丽  我得走了
Oh. Yeah, Emily, I gotta go.
是不是我害你的
Is it because I got you in trouble?
不不  艾米丽  不是你的错
Oh, no. No, Emily, that's not your fault.
我总是要走的
I-I'm always in trouble.
过来
Come here.
答应我要善用你的公主之力  好吗
You make sure you use your princess powers for good, okay?
再见了
Bye.
再见  孩子们
Bye, guys.
我从没想过我会这么说
I never thought I'd say this,
你要走了我心里也不舒服
but I'm sorry to see you leave.
谢谢你这么说  鲁伊兹女士
Thank you very much, Mrs. Ruiz.
叫我莱斯丽就行了
Please call me "Leslie."
如果有新进展的话我会立刻通知你的
I'll contact you if there are any new developments.
-非常感谢  -保重
- I appreciate that. - Take care.
我简直无法相信我看到的
I could not believe what I saw.
我和我老婆吃完午饭回来之后
When my wife and I got back from lunch,
发现门被踹开了
the door was kicked in
整个房间被翻得一团糟
and the place was torn apart.
你知不知道他们在找什么
Do you have any idea what they were looking for?
安东房间天花板的通风孔被撬开了
In Anton's room, the ceiling vent was pried open,
就在下面的地板上
and on the floor right below it.
我发现了这个
I found this.
护照
Passports?
都是空白的
They're blank.
你知道安东怎么会有这些的吗
What was Anton doing with these?
我之前从来没见过这些
I've never seen them before today.
我的儿子究竟卷入什么事情了
What was my son involved in?
他正在进修平面设计
He was studying graphic design.
你觉得他是不是在伪造护照
Do you think he was forging passports?
维托什金先生  我想问你一下
Mr. Vetotchkin, I -- I need to ask you,
你见过这个人吗
do you recognize this man?
见过  这是德米特里  德米特里·拉伦科夫
Yes, that's Dmitri. Dmitri kalenkov.
你是怎么认识他的
And how do you know him?
他和我儿子一起长大的
He and my son grew up together
在阿布哈兹还在战乱的时候
back in Abkhazia during the war.
德米特里也和这事有关吗
Is Dmitri involved in this, too?
抱歉  稍等一下
I'm sorry. Just one moment.
贝克特  你得过来一下
Beckett, you need to come down here.
我发现了线索
I found something.
卡塞尔  把这个塞到你口袋的人...
Castle, whoever put this in your pocket...
在传达一个讯息
Is sending me a message.
我们的证人不太情愿出来作证
Our witness is reluctant to come forward,
但等他发现我要走了
but when they saw I was leaving,
他不得不有所行动
it forced their hand.
你有没有问过是谁画的
Have you tried just asking who drew it?
我不想把他吓跑了
I don't want to scare them off...
不过我有个计划
But I have a plan.
同学们  额外的休息时间到了
Okay, class, time for that extra recess period
这是你们表现好给你们的奖励
I promised you for being extra good today.
我叫艾米丽  你是谁
I'm Emily. Who are you?
我叫凯特  是卡塞尔先生的朋友
I'm kate. I'm Mr. Castle's...friend.
你喜欢和他玩扮公主游戏吗
Do you like to play princess with him?
时不时
Uh...sometimes.
你们俩是不是要结婚
Are you two getting married?
有一天会的
One day. One day.
现在机会来了  我从前面开始找
Now's our chance. I'll take the front.
你们俩从后面开始
You guys take the back.
我们找的是什么
Okay, so what are we looking for?
找一幅可能来自同一个孩子画的画
A drawing that looks like it could have been made by the same kid.
但是这些是一群二年级学生
Yeah, but these are second-graders.
他们的画风都差不多啊
I mean, don't their drawings look the same?
在我看来不是的  探长
Not to me, detective.
当你和这群孩子朝夕相处
When you live and breathe these children,
每一笔画的涂抹都是独一无二的
every scribble is like a fingerprint.
真想不到面对他们还要说这么鼓舞的话
Can't imagine they'll need much prompting when we confront them.
目击的事很显然已经
This has clearly been eating away
被他们脆弱的小心灵给侵蚀了
at their delicate little psyches.
给他们自我倾诉的机会
Given the chance to unburden themselves --
找到了
Found it.
那个脆弱的小心灵是谁
All right. Who's our sensitive little soul?
鲁伊兹老师
Hey, Mrs. Ruiz,
你为什么翻我的桌子
why are you going through my desk?
杰森
Jason?
你是目击证人
You're the witness?
我不会告诉卡塞尔先生的  他是个混球
I'm not talking to Mr. Castle. He's a jerk-face.
好吧  你知道吗
Okay, you know what?
他才是小混球
He's the jerk-face.
他才八岁
He's 8 years old.
你来这才一天半
You've been here for a day and a half,
这么快就拉仇恨了
and you already have a nemesis?
我怎么会知道他就是目击证人
How was I supposed to know he'd be the witness?
杰森
Jason,
我想告诉你你没惹上任何麻烦  好吗
I want you to know that you're not in trouble, okay?
我只不过是画了一幅画
All I did was draw a picture.
没错
Ex-exactly.
但是我知道你想告诉我
But I know that you want to tell me
关于画上的事情
all about this picture.
除非是因为混球在
Except jerk-face over there,
他认为你是胆小鬼所以我们应该
he thinks that you're too scared and that we should
打电话叫你妈妈来接你
call your mom to come and pick you up.
我才不是胆小鬼
I'm not scared!
就是嘛
Told ya.
我要你告诉我藏在冰淇淋卡车的时候
So, listen, I need you to tell me everything that you remember seeing
你看见的所有事情
while you were hiding in this ice cream truck.
我不能说
I-I can't.
杰森  相信我  把心底的秘密说出来
Jason, believe me, it's gonna feel a lot better
会比藏在心里的感觉更好
letting it out rather than keeping it in.
不  我不能说  因为我当时不在那
No! I can't, because I wasn't there!
你不在那
You weren't?
但是我知道是谁
But I know who was.
是谁
Who?
我不该说出来的
I'm not supposed to tell.
杰森  我们只是想帮你
Jason, listen, we just want to help you.
好吗
Okay?
是我姐姐
It was my sister.
好的
Okay.
她也在这里上学吗
Does she go to this school, too?
她是个大人
She's a grownup.
我们是同母异父姐弟
We have different dads.
妈妈出城的时候我和她住在一起
I stay with her when our mom goes out of town.
那天是你把请假条给她的
So you gave her your permission slip that day?
是她让我请假的
She dropped me off
她说她要去见个朋友  一个冰淇淋男
and she said she had to meet her friend, the ice cream man.
当她回到家时 她哭了
When she came home, she was crying.
她跟我说不能告诉任何人她去哪了
She told me never tell anyone where she went,
否则会有坏事发生
or something bad would happen.
你姐姐叫什么名字
What's your sister's name?
娜塔莉·伯恩斯
Natalie Barnes!
我们要你跟我们走一趟
We're gonna need you to come with us.
我从没去过安东的卡车上
I was never in Anton's truck.
我知道你去过  娜塔莉
I know that you were, Natalie.
不管你在害怕什么
Listen, whatever you are scared of,
我都会保护你的
I will protect you,
但你必须告诉我实情
But you have to tell me the truth.
你得从这些你和安东
And you have to start with those passports
一起伪造的护照说起
that you helped Anton forge.
这么说你的确牵涉其中
So you were involved?
我们只是想做点好事
We were just trying to do something good.
你说的"我们"是指谁
Who do you mean by "We"?
-是你  安东  杰菲吗  -是的
- You, Anton, and Jaffe? - Yeah.
告诉我护照的事
Tell me about the passports.
安东的行车路线
Anton's route
覆盖了布莱顿海滩
covered Brighton Beach.
那儿有很多俄国人
There were a lot of Russians there,
他看见了很多人被许诺有工作来到这
and he'd seen so many of them come here with the promise of a job,
然后他们的证件被拿走了
and then their papers would be taken,
他们被迫在血汗工厂工作
and they'd be forced to work in sweatshops
有的则更糟糕
Or -- or worse, and --
安东想让他们回家
Anton was trying to get back home.
但是他们没有合法文件他们回不去
Which they couldn't do now without the right documents.
是的
Yeah.
那杰菲是怎么卷进这件事的
And how did Jaffe fit into all of this?
安东听说杰菲可以通过关系
Well, Anton heard that Jaffe had a connection
拿到空白的护照
that could get blank passports.
而且杰菲在布莱顿海滩当警察
And Jaffe worked Brighton Beach as a cop,
他知道这些都是怎么回事
So he knew what was going on,
他同情那些移民
and -- and he was sympathetic to the immigrants.
而你是拥有
And you were the one
高科技设计软件的人
with the high-tech design software.
所以安东选了你的课
That's why Anton took your class.
当我发现安东的意图时
When I found out what Anton was doing,
我决定帮助他  因为我...
I-I decided to help, 'cause I...
我想做出改变
I wanted to make a difference.
我不明白这事怎么会害死人
I don't understand how this got anyone killed.
有天晚上  安东在班里做护照
The other night, Anton was making a passport in class,
他看见其中一个客户的照片
and he saw the photo of the client,
他认出了那个人  他就是...
and he recognized the man. It was this --
他过去认识的一个很可怕的人
this terrible man from his past.
谁
Who?
安东叫他"上校"
Anton called him "Polkovnik."
安东很害怕他
Anton was terrified of him,
他说这个上校曾想杀了他
said this polkovnik once tried to kill him.
但安东说他必须
But Anton said that he had to --
把照片给一个朋友看才能确认
to show the picture to a friend of his just to be sure,
一个叫德米特里的人
some...guy called Dmitri.
娜塔莉  你在货车里都看见了什么
Natalie, what did you see in that van?
安东给我留了信息
Anton had left a message for me
让我去他的冰淇淋车那见面
to meet him at his ice cream truck,
不是他以往的路线
away from his usual route.
我到那里后  他说杰菲死了
And when I got there, he said that Jaffe was dead,
那个男人杀了他
and that this man had killed him,
如果我们不逃跑的话
and that he was afraid that we would be next
他怕我们会是下一个死的人
if we didn't run.
然后安东看到他过来了
And then Anton saw him coming,
他叫我躲起来
so he told me to hide.
我就眼看着
And I watched.
我眼看着上校开枪打死了安东
I watched as polkovnik gunned Anton down.
你看见他的脸了吗
You see his face?
能描述出来吗
Can you describe him?
是的  我
Yeah, I --
比这更好
I can do...better.
等一下  你说
Wait a second, you're saying
她有上校的照片吗
she's got a picture of polkovnik?
在她公寓的一个信封里
Yeah, in an envelope at her apartment,
还有和那个人相关的其它信息  怎么了
along with other information on him -- why?
因为我们查过这个叫上校的人了
Because we looked into this guy polkovnik.
简单来说  他被通缉不只是因为
Suffice to say he's wanted for a lot more
-杀了三个人那么简单  -在纽约吗
- than just three murders. - Here in New York?
不  在十年前的格鲁吉亚阿布哈兹地区
No, in the Abkhazia region of Georgia 10 years ago.
他因战争罪行被国际法庭通缉
He's wanted by the World Court for war crimes.
他曾是民兵头领  犯下暴行
He was a militia leader, committed atrocities,
血洗很多村庄  包括安东和德米特里住过的
wiped out villages, including where Anton and Dmitri lived.
所以他们才会逃走
That's why they fled.
国际刑警组织一直在追捕这个人
Interpol's been after this guy ever since.
他们得到线报说上校在纽约
They got a tip that polkovnik was in New York,
所以他们加强了抓捕网  但问题是
so they're tightening the net. Only one problem --
没有这个人的照片
there's no pictures of this guy,
没有人知道他长什么样子
so no one knows what he looks like.
他希望可以保持这个状态
And he wants to keep it that way,
所以当德米特里试图自己伸张正义时
so when Dmitri tried to take justice into his own hands,
上校就杀了他
polkovnik killed him.
然后他又追踪到杰菲和安东
Then he tracked down Jaffe and Anton
把他们也杀了
and killed them, too.
他知道他们能够认出他来
He knew that they could I.D. him.
那才是他要找的
That's what he was looking for --
安东准备给他做护照用的照片
The picture that Anton was gonna use on his passport.
他迫切需要护照
A passport that he desperately needs
好离开这个国家
to get out of this country.
好  照片在娜塔莉家里  我们走
Okay, that photo is at Natalie's place. Let's go.
他已经来过了
He's been here.
娜塔莉说照片放在卧室梳妆台
Natalie said it was in the bedroom dresser,
-最下面的抽屉里  -好
- bottom right drawer. - Okay.
不在这  他一定是找到了
It's not here. He must have found it.
不在抽屉里  娜塔莉
It's not in the drawer, Natalie.
照片在一个信封里
The photo was in an envelope.
我藏在一个旧的相机套里
I hid it in an old camera case.
等等  杰森说他在这待过
Wait. Jason said he stayed here
因为他妈妈出城了
because his mom was out of town.
那又怎么样
So?
娜塔莉  那个放信封的相机套
Natalie, the -- the camera case
是不是装拍立得相机的
that you put the envelope in, was it for a polaroid camera?
你怎么知道的
How'd you know?
因为昨天杰森把它带去肯尼迪小学了
Because Jason brought it to Kennedy elementary yesterday
用作展示讲解
for show-and-tell.
那张照片现在就在鲁伊兹老师的教室里
That photo is in Mrs. Ruiz's classroom right now.
找到那张照片  就能抓到上校
We get that photo, we'll get polkovnik.
走吧
Come on.
已经通知联调局  他们的探员已经出发
The F.B.I.'s been notified. They have agents on the way,
他们的作战小队已经将
and their tactical units are sweeping the area
娜塔莉公寓周围的区域搜寻遍了
around Natalie's apartment.
全面通缉进展如何
Where are we on the A.P.B.?
准备好了  联调局准备在早间新闻上发布
Ready to go. The feds want to get this on the evening news.
-现在就等照片了  -五分钟后就到
- all they need is that photo. - You'll have it in five.
好的
Okay.
哪个是杰森的桌子
Okay, which one's Jason's desk?
在这里
Right here.
拿到了
Got it.
在你后面
Behind you.
起来
Get up.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  我摔得比这更惨过
Yeah, I've taken worse.
实际上  就在这间教室里
In this classroom, as a matter of fact.
纸杯蛋糕来咯
Cupcake stampede!
快来拿
Come and get 'em, guys.
给  每人一个  随便拿
Here you go. One for everyone. Help yourselves.
我只是想谢谢你们
This is just a little thank-you to say
陪我度过这段美好的时光
what a wonderful time I had with all of you.
-谢谢  卡塞尔先生  -给  不客气
- Thank you, Mr. Castle. - There you go. You're welcome.
谢谢  卡塞尔先生
Thank you, Mr. Castle.
我会想你们每个人的
I'm gonna miss every one of you.
也包括我吗
Even me?
是的  杰森  也包括你
Yes, Jason, even you.
-咱俩休战怎么样  -好吧
- What do you say? Truce? - Yeah.
-好吧  -休战
- All right. - Truce.
看来你的死对头
Looks like your nemesis isn't ready
还没准备跟你休战
to call it a truce just yet.
是啊  尤其等他看到我在他背后贴的字以后
Yeah. Especially when he sees what I put on his back.
莱斯丽你也来一个吧
Leslie, one for you?
不用了  谢谢
No, thanks.
实际上  我们还给你准备了别的东西
Actually, we have something else for you as well.
这是纽约警局为了感谢你
This is a medal of outstanding service
在追查目击证人中提供的宝贵帮助
from the N.Y.P.D. for your invaluable help
而给你颁的奖章
with tracking down our witness.
杰森的姐姐接下来会怎样呢
What's gonna happen to Jason's sister, anyway?
她同意作证了  有了她的帮助
She's agreed to testify, and with her help,
我们的三个死者和其它很多很多人的正义
our three victims, along with many, many other people
最终得到伸张
will finally get justice.
那你们也许改把这个奖牌颁给她
Then maybe you should give this medal to her.
我没帮上什么忙
I didn't do much to deserve it.
你开什么玩笑
Are you kidding?
你可是忍了卡塞尔整整两天啊
You put up with Castle for two whole days.
我还挺喜欢这个挑战的
I enjoyed the challenge.
以我的经验  最难搞的学生
In my experience, it's the most difficult children
往往是最有成就的
who prove most rewarding.
不是吗  卡塞尔先生
Isn't that right, Mr. Castle?
-卡塞尔先生  -不许最鬼脸  好吧
- Mr. Castle? - No faces. That's right.
谢谢
Thank you.
-再见  -再见J
- See you later. - Later, J.
是我的电话
That's me.
-怎么了  -阿丽克西斯给我发短信
What's wrong? It's Alexis texting me.
放学以后马上回家
"Be sure you come home right after school."
她怎么知道我在学校
How'd she even know I was here right now?
她在我手机上安装了追踪软件
She put one of those tracker apps on my phone!
卡塞尔  这有点过头了
Uh, Castle, uh, this is getting a little out of hand.
是  我得跟她谈谈了
Yeah. I'm gonna have to deal with this.
我想我知道该怎么做
And I think I know how.
爸  你怎么这么晚才回来  学校早就放学了
Dad, what took you so long? School ended hours ago!
阿丽克西斯  宝贝
Alexis, sweetheart --
我担心死了
I've been really worried.
我知道  我知道你为什么这么担心
Yes, I know, and I think I know why.
因为我前段时间失踪了
Because I disappeared.
但  我现在回来了
But...I'm back now,
而且我哪都不会去
and I'm not going anywhere.
我会一直待在这
I'm here to stay.
我老是觉得我会再次失去你
I just keep thinking I'll lose you again,
或者会有什么坏事发生
or something terrible will happen.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I know it sounds crazy --
不  不  一点也不疯狂
No, no, it does not sound crazy.
我也会这么想  实际上  我那时就是这么想的
I would feel the same way. Matter of fact, I did.
在巴黎那件事后
After Paris.
我不敢让你离开我的视线
I couldn't let you out of my sight.
但是
But...
我知道你觉得自己是
I know that you consider yourself
家里的大人
the adult of the family --
我有充分的理由
For good reason.
非常充分的理由
For very good reason.
但是
But...
但是作为大人  就要意识到
But part of being an adult is realizing
你无法永远保护你爱的人
you can't always protect the people you love.
好吧
Okay.
好吗
Okay?
-当大人真讨厌  -是啊
- Being an adult really sucks. - Yeah.
而你当大人的时间太长了
And you've spent way too much time having to be one.
所以
So...
我命令你当个孩子
I'm ordering you to be a kid.
你不觉得我玩这个太老了吗
Don't you think I'm a little old for that?
我都不会太老  所以
I am not too old for it, so you are definitely
你绝对不会
not too old for it.
你不觉得我们至少该试试看吗
Don't you think we should at least test them out?
好吧
Okay.
好的
你想去哪
Where do you want to go?
不知道呢  去吃雪糕
I don't know, ice cream?
披萨怎么样
How about pizza?
这个案子以后  我估计有段时间都不想吃雪糕了
After this case, I might be off ice cream for a while.
好吧
Okay.